我准备蜡烛跟我妈的蕾丝桌布
So, I'll get candles and my mom's lace tablecloth,
既然是瑞秋的生日
and since it's Rachel's birthday,
就要特别点  我想我来煮一条鲑鱼
we want it to be special, I thought I'd poach a salmon.
怎么了
What?
我要问为什么每次开派对  你都要水煮东西
Question. Why do we always have to have parties where you poach things?
你想掌管食物委员会吗
You wanna be in charge of the food committee?
问题二  为什么每次派对都要有食物委员会
Question two. Why do we always have to have parties with committees?
是啊  为什么不买些披萨跟啤酒
Really. Why can't we just get some pizzas and get some beers
大家高兴就好了嘛
and have fun?
我同意  我认为高档派对  只有那些
Yeah, I agree. Ya know, I think fancy parties are only fun
真心高档次的人才玩得开心
if you're fancy on the inside
我们又不是这种人
and I'm just not sure we are.
好吧  你们不想要特别的  随便
Alright. If you guys don't want it to be special, fine.
你们爱怎么样就怎么样
You can throw any kind of party you want.
乔伊  那是假的
Joey they're not real.
我这里面空空如也  这是假的
I start miles beneath the surface of these things, ok, they're fake.
看  空空如也
See, honk honk.
哇  像是给小丑看的黄片
Wow, it's, it's like porno for clowns.
我跟瑞秋的妹妹讲了  她们都不能来
I talked to Rachel's sisters, neither of them can come.
那我还得邀请迪伦  艾玛
Ok, um so, I still have to invite Dillon and Emma
还有夏伦·库珀
and Shannon Cooper.
等等  不能请夏伦·库珀
Woah, woah, woah, uh, no Shannon Cooper.
为什么呢
Why not her?
因为她  偷东西
Cause she uh, she steals stuff.
又或许她不会偷东西
Or maybe she doesn't steal stuff
乔伊跟她上床后  就没再打电话给她了
and Joey just slept with her and never called her back.
乔伊  你太过分了
Joey that is horriable.
我喜欢她  好吗
Hey I liked her, alright.
或许太喜欢了  我不知道
Maybe, maybe too much. I don't know
我想我只是害怕了
I guess I just got scared.
抱歉  我不知道
I'm sorry, I didn't know.
没想到有人会吃这一套
I didn't think anyone'd buy that, ok.
亲爱的  怎么样
Hi honey, how did it go?
如同地狱的毕业典礼一般
Agh, it was the graduation from hell.
我表弟靠着足球奖学金进了地狱
Ya know, my cousin went to hell on a football scholarship.
这本来应该是个快乐的场合
Ya know, I mean this is supposed to be a joyous occasion.
我妹妹从大学毕业了  谁也没想到
My sister's graduating from college, nobody thought she would.
真正证明了
It's a true testament to
一个长岛女孩为了一辆跑车会做什么
what a girl from long island would do for a Celica.
到底怎么了
So what happened?
我宝贝父母呀
My parents happened.
他们只需要坐在同一个体育馆
All they had to do was sit in the same stadium,
骄傲地微笑  绝口不提离婚的事
smile proudly, and not talk about the divorce.
但不  毕业典礼致词到一半时
But nooo, they got into a huge fight
他们就吵得不可开交了
in the middle of the commencement address.
图图主教还得停下来  叫他们两个住口
Bishop Tutu actually had to stop and shush them.
你们知道好消息是什么吗
But you know what, you know what the good news is?
我接着可以帮人倒八小时的咖啡了
I get to serve coffee for the next 8 hours.
那看来不能邀请她父母了
Ok, so I guess we don't invite her parents.
只邀请她妈妈怎么样
Well, how bout just her mom?
为什么
Why her mom?
因为我已经请了
Cause I already invited her.
你请了史戴西·罗丝吗
Ooh, ooh, did you ask Stacy Roth?
不  不能邀请她
Oh no, can't invite her.
她也会偷东西
She also steals.
这是生日蛋糕的蜡烛  生日蛋糕呢
Ok, here are the birthday candles. Where's the birthday cake?
我们不吃生日蛋糕  我们吃生日果冻饼
Ok, we're not having birthday cake, we're having birthday flan.
什么
Excuse me?
这是一种传统的墨西哥奶油冻甜点
It's a traditional Mexican custard dessert.
不错呀  生日快乐  瑞秋  来些膏
Oh that's nice. Happy birthday Rachel, here's some goo.
格林医生  老天啊  是瑞秋的爸爸
Dr. Green. Oh my God it's Rachel's dad.
你来做什么
What're you doing here?
怎么了  女儿生日老爸过来看看也不行吗
What? The father can't drop by to see the daughter on her birthday?
不是啦  老爸当然可以
No no, the father can, but um,
但因为我是她室友  我可以告诉你她不在
since I am the roommate I can tell you that she's not here
我会转告她你来过了  所以  拜拜
and I'll pass along the message, ok. So bye-bye.
你们开派对呀
Ohhh, you're having a parteee.
不  不是派对啦
No, no, not a party.
只是一群瑞秋认识的人的惊喜聚会
Just a surprise gathering of some people Rachel knows.
这是菲比  钱德勒  乔伊
Um, this is Phoebe and Chandler and Joey.
太多人了我记不住  什么安排
I'll never remember all of that. So uh, what's the deal?
瑞秋回来  大家跳出来尖叫
Rachel comes home, people pop out and yell stuff,
是不是这样
is that it?
这不是你的第一个惊喜派对吧  先生
This isn't your first surprise party, is it sir?
你好  莫妮卡
Hi Monica.
送中餐馆菜单的  他忘了菜单了
Chinese menu guy. Forgot the menus.
所以基本上只是个中国人而已
So, basically just a Chinese guy.
格林医生
Uh, hey, Dr. Green,
你跟我来好了  我们把外套放瑞秋床上
why don't you come with me, we'll put your jacket on Rachel's bed.
好啊  这似乎需要两个人
Alright, that sounds like a two person job.
我的天  你刚干嘛啊
Well, my goodness, what was that?
桑德拉  真对不起
Sandra, I am so sorry,
我以为你是瑞秋  可是我们还没准备好
I thought you were Rachel and we just weren't ready for you yet.
你以为我是瑞秋
You thought I was Rachel?
对啊  你看起来好年轻
Yes because uh, you look so young.
而且你们两个都是  白种女人
And because you're both, you know, white women.
我好想念你们  我应该把外套放房间吗
Oh, I missed you kids. Well, should I put my coat in the bedroom?
不  交给我就好了
No! No, I'll take that for ya.
那就谢了  真是个绅士啊  谢谢
Oh well thank you. Such a gentleman. Thank you.
看起来真棒  喜气洋洋的
Ahh, it all looks so nice, so festive,
那么多气球
all the balloons...
我过来的时候碰到
The funniest thing happened to me
一件好可笑的事  我...
on the way here. I was...
太棒了
Ha-ha, that's great.
我等不及听你说完
I can't wait to hear the rest of it, ya know,
但我实在要去洗手间了
but I really have to go to the bathroom so...
-跟我来吧  -什么
- Hey, come with me. - What?
就像我们是好姐妹
Yeah, yeah, it'll be like we're gal pals,
在餐厅一起去洗手间
ya know, like at a restraunt.
会很好玩的  来吧
Oh, it'll be fun, c'mon.
天啊...
Oh my God, oh my God, oh my God.
快想一想  杰克和克里丝会怎么做
Ok, think, what would Jack and Chrissy do?
你的外套已经安全放到床上了
Ok, now that your coat is safely in the bedr-,
我们现在可以回客厅了
oh, ok we can come back out in the living room.
对了  乔伊  钱德勒
So uh, Joey and Chanlder,
我想你们应该带格林医生到你们那边去
I, I think it's time that you take Dr. Green over to your place.
对  完全正确  为什么
Uhh, yes, absdolutely, um. Why again?
因为派对在那边呀  笨蛋
Because that's where the party is you goon.
这边只是准备区
See this is just the staging area.
只是准备区
Right this is staging.
对  只是准备区而已
Yeah, this more than anything else, is the staging area.
这个显然挂错地方了
This is clearly in the wrong apartment.
好吧  你们这些人去一号派对
Alright you guys are off to party number one
而你们呢  去二号派对
and you, you are off to party number two.
伙计们  继续走  继续走
Alright fellas, let's keep it movin', let' keep it movin.
钱德勒  你好歹放几个女的来这边好吗
Chandler could you at least send some women to my party?
是罗斯
Okay, that's Ross.
他们来了  安静
Ok, they're coming, shhh.
谢谢你这顿美妙的晚餐
Ohh, thank you for the wonderful dinner.
谢谢你出生
Thanks for being born.
谢谢你这对漂亮的耳环
Ohh, thank you for my beautiul earrings,
真的好美  我爱你
they're perfect. I love you.
你想的话可以拿去换
Oh, now you can exchange them if you want, ok.
现在我更爱你了
Now I love you even more.
惊喜
Surprise.
天啊  莫妮卡
Oh my gosh, wow. Monica.
天啊  妈  太棒了
Oh my god. Mom. This is so great.
生日快乐  亲爱的
Happy birthday sweetie.
瞧你  我完全不知道呢
Wow you, you. I had no idea.
真的
Really?
不  我知道的
No, I knew.
好
All right.
各位  桌上有吃的喝的  去对面
Ok, everybody, there's food and drinks on the table. Go across the hall.
-什么  -现在去乔伊跟钱德勒那边  快
- What? - Right now, Joey and Chandler's, go now.
为什么
Why.
去就是了
Just go.
惊喜
Surprise.
生日快乐  小甜豆
Happy birthday sweetpea.
爸爸
Daddy.
他们都来了  两个都来了吗
Both of them are here, both of them, both of them are here?
我们可以再算一次
Well, we could count again.
我无法相信有这种事
I can't believe this is happening.
这太荒唐了
You know what, this is ridiculous, ok.
这是你的生日  你的派对
This is your birthday, this is your party.
我说把他们放在一起
I say we just put 'em all together
如果他们互相看不顺眼  谁在乎
and if they can't deal with it, who cares.
我在乎
I do.
就是你
That's who.
你不要紧吧
Look, are you gonna be ok?
我根本就别无选择嘛
Well, I have to be, I don't really have a choice,
我可以往好的方面想啊
I mean, you know, I could look at the bright side,
我有两个生日派对  还有两个生日蛋糕
I get two birthday parties and two birthday cakes.
其实只有一个生日果冻饼
Well, actually just one birthday flan.
什么
What?
那是一种传统的墨西哥奶油冻甜点
It's a traditional Mexican custard dessert...
去问莫妮卡吧  她是食物委员会的人
Look talk to Monica, she's on the food committee.
乔伊  乔伊
Joey, Joey.
有个女的刚刚走过来跟我说
Hey, some girl just walked up to me and said,
"我要你  丹尼斯"
'I want you Dennis,'
然后给了我一个热吻
and stuck her tounge down my throat.
我爱这个派对
I love this party.
很好  我有个排球问题
Nice. Quick volleyball question.
排球
Volleyball.
我们在你房间弄了个球场
Yeah, we set up a court in your room.
你不会很喜欢那盏灰色台灯吧
Uh, you didn't really like that grey lamp, did you?
乔伊  刚才有个女人给了我一个热吻
Joey, a woman just stuck her tounge down my throat,
我根本就没听你说话
I'm not even listening to you.
丹尼斯
Dennis.
她在叫我了
Ok, that's me.
亲爱的  你陪我爸一下好吗
Listen honey, can you keep dad occupied,
我要去跟我妈讲一下话
I'm gonna go talk to mom for a while.
那我用什么话当开场白呢
Ok, do you have any ideas for any openers?
只要避开"我是那个上你女儿的人"
Uhh, let's just stay clear of 'I'm the guy that's doing you daughter'
就不会有问题了
and you should be ok.
各位  大家一人拿一张纸
Ok people, I want you to take a piece of paper,
拿去  然后写下你们最糗的回忆
here you go, and write down your most embarassing memory.
请各位在用完马克笔之后
Oh, and I do ask that when you're not using the markers,
把笔盖盖上  不然的话笔会干掉
you put the caps back on them because they will dry out.
格林医生
Hi Dr. Green.
一切都还好吗
So, uh, how's everything in the uh,
血管外科游戏那边
vascular surgery....game?
那不是游戏  罗斯
It's not a game Ross,
今天有个女人死在我的手术台上
a woman died on my table today.
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
这就是我工作的好处
See that's the good thing about my job.
我的工作台上的那些恐龙  都已经死了
All the dinosaurs on my table are already dead.
听着各位  我并不是故意要烦你们
Listen you guys, I don't mean to be a pain about this
但我注意到  刚刚有些人只是套上
but, um, I've noticed that some of you are just placing them on.
应该要用力按
You wanna push the caps
听到喀的一声为止
until you hear them click.
甘瑟  你要去哪里啊
Gunther, where're you going?
我  我只是在想  或许我...
I um, was sorta thinking about maybe...
不  你不能走  不行  这很好玩
No. No you can't go. No this is fun.
来嘛  我们才刚开始
Come on we're just getting started.
给  这是你的笔
Here, here's your marker.
听着  你想走就走好了
Listen if you wanna go, just go.
不  她会再吼我的
No, she'll yell at me again.
好吧  我可以把你弄出去
Alright, I can get you out.
什么
What?
等一下我们来个声东击西
Shh. In a minute, I'm gonna create a diversion.
到时候  你赶快朝门走  不要回头
When I do, walk quickly to the door and don't look back.
我想来杯喝的
I think I need a drink.
我去帮你拿  你要喝什么
Oh, here, I, I'll get it for ya. Whad'ya want?
威士忌
Scotch.
威士忌  好  我十秒钟之内
Scotch. Alright, I'll be back in 10 seconds
会带着你的威士忌加冰块回来
with your scotch on the rocks in a glass.
纯
Neat.
正
Cool.
不是  纯的  不加冰块
No no no, no no no, neat, as in no rocks.
我知道
I know.
罗斯  你上哪儿去了
Oh hello Ross, where have you been?
我一直在洗手间
Hi. Uh, I have been in the bathroom.
避开那些鲑鱼慕斯
Stay clear of the salmon mousse.
纯威士忌
Oh, scotch neat.
瑞秋她爸就爱这玩意儿
Ya know, that's Rachel's father's drink.
我也是
Oh, mine too.
很正对吗  纯威士忌
Isn't that neat, scotch neat.
我先失陪了
Would you excuse me?
你想溜到哪里去呢  先生
Hey, hey, where you uh, sneakin off to mister?
我要去拿我外套里的香烟
I'm getting my cigarettes out of my jacket.
不行
No. no.
什么意思啊
Whad'ya mean no?
因为那边是准备区
No, um, see 'cause that, that is, that is the staging area.
你一去的话  就不会觉得派对梦幻了
If you go in there, it'll ruin the whole illusion of the party.
你还是带着你的威士忌回去
Yeah, I think you take your scotch back in there
我会帮你拿香烟的  先生
and I will get your cigarettes for you sir.
还有我的眼镜
Get my glasses too.
有我就搞定了
All righty roo.
真是第一次说那句话的好时机
What a great moment to say that for the first time.
第一个人的最糗回忆就是
Ok, the first person's most embarassing memory is,
"莫妮卡  你的派对好烂"  非常幽默
'Monica, your party sucks.' Very funny.
不好  天啊  有人忘了用杯垫吗
Oh no, ooh, ooh, did somebody forget to use a coaster?
什么
What?
我没看到有水迹啊
I don't see anything.
这下可好  我的眼睛又花了
Great, I'm seeing water rings again.
罗斯  这是谁的眼镜啊
Ross, whose glasses are those?
我的
Mine.
你戴远近两用的眼镜
You wear bi-focals?
我的视力  显然同时
I have a condition, apparently,
需要用到两种镜片
that I require two different sets of focals.
你知道我先生也有一副一样的眼镜吗
Did you know my husband has glasses just like that?
这副镜框很流行
Well those are very popular frames.
尼尔·萨达卡也有一副(著名歌星  钢琴家)
Neil Sedaka wears them.
听说你有办法弄我们出去
I hear you can get people out of here.
瑞秋  你可没告诉我你男友抽烟
Rachel, you didn't tell me your boyfriend smoked.
对  像烟囱
Yeah, like a chimney.
大烟枪
Ohh, big smoker.
超大烟枪
Big big smoker.
事实上  我现在就要去走廊上
In fact I'm gonna go ou into the hallway
点燃这根大坏蛋
and fire up this bad boy.
你戴的是我的眼镜吗
Are you wearing my glasses?
对
Yes.
我只是替你把那个耳架弄暖一点
I was just warming up the earpieces for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
那是我的香烟吗
Is that one of my cigarettes?
对  没错
Yeah, yes it is,
我只是把这个烟屁股弄湿
I was just moistening the tip.
好了  她去倒垃圾了
Ok, ok, she's taking the trash out
我可以弄你们出去  但必须是现在
so I can get you out of here but it has to be now,
她随时会回来
she'll be back any minute.
那我朋友维克多呢
What about my friend Victor?
不行  只能你们三个
No, only the three of you,
超过了她会起疑心的
any more than that and she'll get suspicious.
好吧  我去拿外套
Alright, let me just get my coat.
没有时间了
There isn't time.
什么都不要拿  隔壁那些人会照顾你们的
You must leave everything. They'll take care of you next door.
他们有啤酒是真的吗
Is it true they have beer?
你们听到的都是真的
Everything you've heard is true.
你们小声一点  好不好
Could you guys please try to keep it down,
我们要来个文字游戏锦标赛
we're trying to start a Boggle tournament.
你  还有你  你们应该在我的派对啊
You, and you, you're supposed to be at my party.
还有甘瑟
And Gunther!
你在这个地方干什么啊
What are you doing here?
欢迎光临...
Ok, welcome to the fu-oh.
菲比
Phoebe.
好了  对不起嘛  可是这些人需要我
Alright, I'm sorry but these people needed me.
他们辛苦了一个礼拜  今天是周六
They work hard all week, it's Saturday night,
他们有权享乐一下  去吧
they deserve to have a little fun. Go.
我的派对很好玩
Ya know, my party is fun.
或许是安静了一点  比较含蓄的乐趣
I mean, maybe it's a little quieter, less obvious sorta fun,
但如果大家给一个机会...
but, you know, if people would just give it a chance...
你要我去看心理医生
You want me to see a therapist?
亲爱的  你显然有问题了
Sweetheart, you obviously have a problem.
你居然选了一个  跟你爸一模一样的男朋友
You've chosen a boyfriend exactly like your father.
妈  好的  我会去预约时间的
Ok mom, you know what, fine, I'll make an appointment ok,
现在我得走了  我得去做一件事
but you know what, right now, I gotta go, I gotta go do a thing.
你知道吗  你老妈居然花了
Did you know your mother spent
一千二百块买一个盆栽
$1200 dollars on bansai trees.
我觉得我好像在小人国的森林里
I felt like Gulliver around that place.
爸  你知道吗
Daddy, daddy, you know what,
我真的很想再多听听  真的
I really wanna hear more about this, I really do,
但我有点事要处理下
but I just have, I just have to do a, some stuff.
我一直很努力很努力想要挽救这段婚姻
You work and you work and you work at a marriage
可是他只关心他那艘破船
but all he cares about is his stupid boat.
我一直很努力很努力去照顾我的船
You work and you work and you work on a boat...
他总是嘲笑我的陶艺课
He always ridiculed my pottery classs...
磨好了之后还要上漆
...and you sand it and you varnish it...
说归说  他还是用我做的杯子喝东西
...but when all is said and done, he still drinks out of the mugs.
听她唠叨一晚的瑜珈  还有她的《廊桥遗梦》
One night and her yoga and her Bridges of Madison County...
威士忌  香烟
...the scotch and the cigarettes...
盆栽  吉娃娃狗
...and the bansai's and the chiuaua...
我只看了三个星期的心理医生  但...
...I may have only been in therapy for three weeks now dear but...
她要半条船干什么
...what the hell does she want with half a boat...
你衣服留着我光着身子好了
Ok, ok, you can be shirts and I'll be skins.
我光身子呀
I'll be skins.
你没事吧  虎仔
Hey, how you holdin' up there, tiger?
抱歉  我父母闹离婚时
Oh, sorry, when my parents were getting divorced
很多人叫我"虎仔"
I got a lot of tigers.
还有不少"冠军"  "老大"  "好手"
Got a lot of champs, chiefs, sports,
还有人叫我"州长"
I even got a governor.
就这样了  是不是
This is it, isn't it?
我的生活就会变成这样了
I mean, this is what my life is gonna be like.
我妈跟我爸一人一个地方
My mom there, my dad there.
感恩节  圣诞节
Thanksgiving, Christmas.
她得到房子
She gets the house,
他住在公寓  我妹打算用柳条家具帮他布置
he's in some condo my sister's gonna decorate with wicker.
钱德勒  你是怎么熬过来的
Oh, Chandler how did you get through this?
我依靠的是精心策划的计划
Well, I relied on a carefully regimented program
拒绝面对现实
of denial
还有尿床
and, and wetting the bed.
这太奇怪了
Ya know, I just, so weird.
我在里面  听着他们两个人骂来骂去
I mean I was in there just listening to them bitch about each other
可是心里却一直在想着国庆日
and all I kept thinking about was the fourth of July.
因为那让你想起我们的先辈
Becasue it reminded you of the way
从前也是骂来骂去吗
our forefathers used to bitch at each other?
是这样的  我们每年都会坐我爸的船出海
It's just this thing. Every year we would go out on my dad's boat
去看烟火
and watch the fireworks.
我妈总是讨厌去
Mom always hated it
因为海风会把她的头发吹膨
because the ocean air made her hair all big.
我妹妹吉尔  则会靠在船边呕吐
My sister Jill would be throwing up over the side
我爸会生气  因为没有人帮他忙
and my dad would be upset becasue nobody was helping
当我们帮忙时  他又会大吼说我们越帮越忙
and then when we did help he would scream at us for doing it wrong.
但是当烟火开始后  大家都闭嘴了
But then when the fireworks started, everybody just shut up,
然后会变得很冷
you know, and it'd get really cold,
我们会全部挤在一条毯子下面
and we would all just sort of smush under this one blanket.
从来没有人想到要多带一条来
It never occured to anybody to bring another one.
但是现在
And now it's just...
对  我知道
Yeah, I know.
谢谢光临  希望你们玩得开心
Ok, thanks for coming, I hope you guys had fun.
好了  莫妮卡  我要走了
Alright, Monica dear, I'm gonna hit the road.
我把十个动词放在你桌上了
Now I've left my 10 verbs on the table.
一定要把完成的诗寄给我
And you be sure and send me that finished poem.
我会的  很高兴你来了
Ok will do. So glad you came.
我想我看到瑞秋在走廊上
I think I saw Rachel out in the hall.
-我去看看  -好的
- Ok, let me go check. - All right.
你妈要跟你道别了
Your mom want's to say goodbye.
生日快乐  亲爱的
Happy birthday sweetie.
小心开车
Ahh, you drive safe.
罗斯  你在干嘛
Ross, what're you doing.
我正在为去滑水做准备
I'm getting ready for the water skiing.
再抱下  来嘛  再抱下
Big hug, come on, big hug.
你好吗
How are you?
格林医生  你要去哪里
Well, uh, Dr. Green, where are you going?
拿我的外套
To get my coat.
-不用  -我去拿
- No no no. - I'll get it.
好了  我可以自己去拿
Alright, alright, I can get my own coat.
抱歉  果冻饼让我们爽歪了
Sorry, we're on a major flan high.
不行  你不应该来这里的
Oh no, you're not supposed to be here.
这里是准备区  这样不对
This is the staging area, you should, it's all wrong,
你应该走  出去就是了
you should leave, ya know, just get out.
要不要来杯薄荷酒啊
Or perhaps you'd like a creme d'menthe.
我必须打道回府了  谢了
I have to be heading to my chateau, thank you.
好吧  那我猜我们又要回到走廊了
Oh all right, then I guess we're going back into the hallway.
谢谢光临  格林太太
Thanks for coming Mrs. Green.
好了  你保重哦
Well, ok, you take care.
你们这些孩子
Oh, you kids.
好啦
Well,
我好久没有参加过这么棒的派对了
this is the best party I've been to in years.
谢谢
Thank you.
各位  切果冻饼了
Ok everybody, it's time for flan.
对  准备享用冻冻乐了
Yup, get ready for the gelatenous fun.
看起来有点像伤口发炎时化的脓
Kinda looks like that stuff you get when you get a bad infection.
好了  够了
Ok, that's enough.
瑞秋  许个果冻饼愿吧
Ok Rachel, make a special flan wish.
好了
Ok, I've got one.
小心
Head up.
哇  居然有愿望成真的时候
Wow, those things almost never come true.